

# JUSLIN JACOB

CONTACT

PHONE: 8837507012

9464187878

**EMAIL:** 

j.jacob2330@gmail.com

To whosoever it may concern,

I am writing to apply for post of mental health professional and trainer.

I am confident that I have skills and qualifications that you are looking for, and I am eager to put my experience and learning to work in new and challenging environment as well as contributing to your organization's vision and goals.

I have been working as MHP for almost 3 years and during this time period I have gained extensive experience in assessing and diagnosing mental health disorders, providing therapy and counseling services, and conducting research on mental health issues. I am also well-versed in using various assessment tools and therapeutic techniques.

I am confident that I can be a valuable asset to your team, and I look forward to the opportunity to discuss my qualifications in further detail. I have attached my resume. Looking forward to work you.

Sincerely

Juslin Jacob

# **Juslin Jacob**

Jalandhar, Punjab. Contact No. 9464187878



A positive attitude person with full passion and dedication to work in any atmosphere.

From last three years, I have worked with a wide range of patients, including children, adolescents, adults and geriatric population. I have also worked with patients who suffer from a variety of mental health issues, including depression, anxiety, bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, OCD, conversion disorders. My experience has taught me how to work with people who are suffering from these conditions, and it has also given me the skills necessary to help them manage their symptoms so that they can lead productive lives.

I have experience working in a variety of settings, including school environment, private practice, inpatient psychiatry, and outpatient mental health clinics. I am skilled in providing evidence-based treatments, such as Psychoeducation, cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT), dialectical behavior therapy (DBT), Behavior Therapy (BT) and mindfulness-based interventions.

I am also experienced in providing assessment such as IQ assessments, childhood behavior assessments, neuropsychological assessments, memory test, Rorschach Inkblot test etc. as well as diagnosis of mental health disorders.

I am confident that my experience will allow me to be an asset to your organization. I am also confident that my ability to build strong relationships with patients will allow me to provide them with the care that they need. I am an approachable psychotherapist with a knack for making people feel at ease. I am also proficient at completing progress notes and keeping track of paperwork.

I believe that "Success usually comes to those who are too busy to be looking for it."

# **Educational qualification:**

• Qualified UGC NET for **Assistant professor** in year 2019

Qualification	Programme	Name of Institute	University/ Board	Year From - To	%ge	Division
	MPhil Clincial Psychology	Dayanand Medical College & Hospital, Ludhiana	Baba Farid University & RCI affiliation	2020-2022	72 %	First Division
Post- Graduation	M.Sc (Psychology with Clinical specialization)	Kristu Jayanti College (Autonomous), Bengaluru	Bangalore University	2017-2019	83.07%	First class with distinction (First Rank)
Graduation	B.Sc (Psychology)	Mother Arts and Science College, Thrissur, Kerala	Calicut University	2014-2017	85.56%	First Div. with distinction
12 <sup>th</sup>	Super Medical with Biology and Math	St. Joseph Boys" School, Jalandhar, Punjab	CICSE	2013	61.8	First class
10 <sup>th</sup>		St. Joseph Convent School	ICSE	2011	76.71	Distinction

## **Experience:**

Period	Organization	Roles & Responsibilities
Oct 2022- Sept 2023	ANR Neuropsychiatric Hospital, Jalandhar	<ul> <li>Dealing with patients with various mental health issues and disorders on OPD and IPD basis</li> <li>Diagnosis and evaluation of mental and emotional disorders through clinical interviews and assessments</li> <li>Selecting, administering and interpreting psychological assessments</li> <li>Forming treatment plan; select treatment approach; therapeutic techniques</li> <li>Instruct, direct and teach students serving internship programs</li> <li>Documenting and keeping records of clients</li> </ul>

Oct 2020 – Oct 2022	Dayanand Medical College and Hospital, Ludhiana	<ul> <li>Supported numerous patients in IPD and OPD basis</li> <li>Helped assisting in activities of daily living (ADLs) and promote patient's psychological well-being</li> <li>Psychological testing such s personality tests, projective tests, IQ tests and more</li> <li>Formulation and administration of therapeutic interventions</li> <li>Testing and assessment of behavioral health issues</li> </ul>
April 2020- January 2021 (10 months)	Abundant Life group, Ludhiana	<ul> <li>Teaching and training of psychology students and aspirants</li> <li>Individual counseling session under supervision</li> <li>Conducting webinar/seminars</li> <li>Facilitator/ supervisor of the internees</li> </ul>
July 2020- October 2020 (4 months)	Lecturer (Psychology) YS School, Barnala	<ul> <li>Teaching and training Class 11<sup>th</sup> and 12<sup>th</sup> grade covering CBSE syllabus</li> </ul>
Sept 2020- October 2020	Sophia Girls" College, Ajmer	<ul> <li>Conducting lectures for graduate students</li> <li>Covering Abnormal psychology, social psychology, research Methodology</li> </ul>
45 days	Clinical Psychology intern at K.I.M.S Hospital and Research Centre, Bangalore	<ul> <li>Interviewing and Taking detailed case history</li> <li>Various assessments such a scales, rating scales, projective tests conducted</li> <li>Provisional diagnosis provided after discussing with senior and Formulation of treatment plan         Psycho- educating the client and family also JPMR sessions conducted     </li> <li>Conducted various psychotherapy classes for MD Students (psychiatry)</li> </ul>
20 days	Neil Hospital, Jalandhar (Clinical Psychology intern)	<ul> <li>Assisted senior psychologist in case history taking</li> <li>Case discussion with the psychiatrist</li> </ul>

2 months on weekly basis	Lovedale Foundation	<ul> <li>Education under privileged children of KG section</li> <li>Teach them various rhymes and action songs</li> <li>Engage in creative activities for teaching manners and life skills</li> <li>Teaching their subjects in creative ways</li> </ul>
2 months  – on weekly basis	Sisters of Mercy of the Holy Cross (Old Age Home) for destitute women	<ul> <li>Interaction and conducting various physical activities to encourage minimal body activity</li> <li>Provide listening ear to their life stories.</li> <li>Conduct recreational activities</li> </ul>
4 months  – weekly basis	Daya Niketan Sons of Divine Providence	<ul> <li>Dealt with intellectually challenged student and those with other behavioural and psychological issues</li> <li>Observe the classes being taken for the students and assisted students in doing their work</li> <li>Assist the teachers in the specific classes such as art and craft,</li> </ul>
		<ul> <li>language and gardening</li> <li>To supervise the students during their exercise and dance sessions and computer training.</li> </ul>
One day session	St. Michael"s High School	<ul> <li>Interaction with students of Std 8and 9</li> <li>Gave short class on life skills</li> <li>Various activities were conducted</li> </ul>

## **Research work:**

- Graduate dissertation on "Empty Nest Syndrome in working and non-working women
- Post graduate thesis on "Internet Addiction, Locus of Control and Resilience"
- **Article published**: "Internet Addiction, Locus of Control and Resilience" in Artha Journal Christ University
- Case report on "Trichotillomania- Out with the Old, in with the new": Published
- MPhil dissertation on "Defense mechanism and its association with Quality of Life, Resilience and Depression in patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.

• **Article** on "Defense mechanism and its association with Quality of Life, Resilience and Depression in patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus – Publication process on- going

## **Presentation and participation**

S.No	Name of Conference/seminars	Title of the paper	Participation /presentation
1.	National Conference "Insight 2018" on the theme "Wellness: A Multidimensional Approach towards Sustainable Development", Bangalore.	Relationship between parent adult- child relationship and general well-being among college Students	Presented
2.	Interdisciplinary Inter-Collegiate Fest "Amalgam", Dept. of Psychology, St. Agnes College (Autonomous), Mangaluru	-	Participated
3.	Two- day workshop on "Advance Counsellor training", Bangalore	-	Participated
4.	Workshop on "Stroke: Awareness and Prevention"- Dept of Mental Health Education, NIMHANS, Bangalore.	-	Participated
5.	Workshop on "Life Skills for Mental health Professionals"- Centre for Life	-	Participated
	Skills Education (CLSE) at Kristu Jayanti College, Bengaluru		
6.	3 <sup>rd</sup> Annual Drishti Symposium – Drishti, Bangalore	-	Participated

## **Awards and Recognition:**

- Secured **First Rank** in Master's degree in Psychology with clinical specialization.
- Article published: "Internet Addiction, Locus of Control and Resilience" in Journal Christ University
- Participated in Intra- Collegiate Literary and Cultural Fest for Post Graduate students organized by Kristu Jayanti College, Bengaluru and secured second prize in Mime event.
- Participated in Inter-collegiate Annual Fest Suicide Prevention and Awareness and secured First place in Mime event.
- Also participated in various other extra-curricular activities held at Mother Arts and Science College, Thrissur, Kerala
  - Secured Second place in Republic Day Quiz Competition

- Secured First place in English Essay writing on Arts
- Secured Second place in 100m race for Girls on Sports Day
- Secured Third place in Eastern Group song event on Arts
- Secured First place in Essay writing event on Republic Day Celebration
- Secured Second place in Hindi Reading Competition
- Secured First place in Hindi Essay writing on Arts Day

### **Other Responsibilities:**

- Organized Intra-Collegiate Fest "Cognizance" conducted by Dept. of Psychology at Kristu Jayanti College on 10<sup>th</sup> August 2017.
- Assisted at Bengaluru Sports Meet 2017 for Persons with intellectual dis-Ability held on 30<sup>th</sup> August 2017 at Sree Kanteerva Stadium, Bangalore.
- Organized National Level Inter- Collegiate Psychology Fest "Stimuli 2017" held on 20<sup>th</sup> September 2017.
- Organized National Conference "Insight 2018" on the theme "Wellness: A Multidimensional Approach towards Sustainable Development" held on January 30 & 31, 2018 at Kristu Jayanti College.
- Organized Intra- Collegiate Psychology fest "Cognizance 2018" held on 17<sup>th</sup> August, 2018 at Kristu Jayanti College, Bengaluru

## **Key competencies and Skills:**

#### Professional

- In depth understanding of the Mental Health Act.
- Experience of Microsoft software like Word, Excel and PowerPoint. Able to manage complex case loads.
- Experience of working with adolescent children.
- Proven organizational and administrative ability
- Preparing and maintaining patient records.
- Can identify whether and when patients are at risk of harming themselves or others.

#### Personal

- Good communication skills and professional approach to work.
- Flexible and able to work independently.
- Possessing a confident and articulate manner.
- Able to respond to distressed patients in a non-threatening manner.
- Ability to stay calm under pressure.
- Able to react quickly and effectively when dealing with challenging situations.

### **Personal information:**

DOB -30/07/1994

Marital status - Married

Husband name – Dr. Jijo Philip Abraham

Languages Known – English, Hindi, Punjabi and Malayalam

Nationality - Indian